I have a question for you using
JavaScript how long do you think it will
take you to format this date into Korean
format or German or Arabic what about
taking a number and displaying it as a
currency
how long do you think it will take you
to take a number and format it in a
social media friendly way what about
taking another number and formatting it
to relative time without using any
Library how long would that take you I
know how long it would take me one line
of code and that is thanks to an API
that not many people know about called
the internationalization API the
internationalization API has a lot of
super useful functions that allow us to
format dates numbers and even lists into
the different languages and formats of
the world the internationalization API
has many different Constructors that
format different things the date time
format Constructor helps us format date
and time to use it first we need a date
then we initialize the date time format
Constructor with the locals that we want
to format our date to and then we call
the format method with the date we
created before
that will format our date according to
the local that we chose the daytime
format Constructor also supports options
if we want to we can specify how the
time and the date should look like in
this case with a date style set to
medium and time style set to full we
will get an output like this
you could even use a different calendar
if you wanted to and you will get
something like this
you can customize exactly how each unit
weekday year month hour minute and
seconds should be formatted with options
like these ones we can expect an output
that looks like this
in your options you can specify the time
zone and you can also choose if you want
to use the 12 hour format or not so if
you have a date in Korean time zone and
you want to show your customers in
America what time that would be all you
have to do is use the time zone name and
your users will see that date on their
time zone number format is another
Constructor that as you can guess helps
us format numbers the API is very
similar to the date time format instead
of update we use a number then we call
the Constructor with a local and we call
the format method
to get an output like this
the power of the number format is on the
options we can pass for example we can
format our numbers as a currency by
specifying this style and currency
options to get an output like this
and we can also choose how the currency
should be displayed to get an output
like this we can round amounts as well
getting this output
we can also for example format our
numbers as units like kilometers per
hour by specifying the style and unit
options that code will give us an output
like this one there are a lot of units
like for example litter giving us an
output like this
or gigabyte that looks like this
to format the numbers like the counters
we see in social media all we have to do
is set the notation option to compact
that will give us something like this
we also have other types of notations
like scientific notation or engineering
notation that look like this
a Constructor that maybe you did not
know you needed until today is the list
format Constructor list format allows
you to format lists if we have a list of
fruits like this one we can use list
format like the other Constructors
passing a local and some options and
that will give us an output like this
we can change the type from Conjunction
to this Junction and we will get
something like
this if you don't want to get and or or
to display units for example you can
change the type to unit getting
something like this
the last Constructor we are going to see
is relative time format this Constructor
allows you to format a number into one
day ago or in one month or after
tomorrow we use it like we use all the
other Constructors except that when we
call the format method we have to
specify what unit we want to format on
so with a code like this we get an
output like this if we pass a negative
number to the format function the format
will change to the Past
getting an output like this
that's it for this video I hope that you
found it useful and I hope that you
start using the internationalization API
if you haven't used it already let me
know in the comments what do you think
about this API are you already using it
are you going to use it I'm very curious
to know and don't forget that if you
want to learn things like JavaScript
python react react native go start
flutter among many others for absolutely
free all you have to do is click the
link below to join any of our many free
courses that you can take right now for
absolutely free with me click the link
below and I will see you there
see you on the next one bye